(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-23T23:37:31.902939",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
TODAY...
5/11 2026 RAORA'S BIRTHDAY
Chattini, let's celebrate together!
May 11, 2026 — Raora's Birthday
BEGINS
Oh my, that was a good nap!
Wait... Wait a minute...
That's not my room. Huh?
Why... Why am I... What's going on?
How did I end up here?
What? A... white canvas?
Huh? What is this? Why... Why is there a white canvas in here?
Eh? Wh- Where is my room? Huh?
Weird.
Huh? Chotino!
Ah! Thank God you're here!
Oh, th-this place is so scary, Chotino, where are we?
Chotino? Cho... Chotino!
What happened to you?
Come here, don't worry, I got you.
You are kind of heavy, though!
Don't worry, Chotino, I got you. We need to find a way out, okay?
We're gonna find a way out.
Oh, where... where should we go?
Ah! Why is there a portal now?
You opened it? No?
Fine, I guess we should go in there.
Maybe I'm gonna wake up? Maybe I'm still dreaming.
Okay. Eisho! Let's go!
You are kind of heavy, though. Eisho!
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
A lonely girl is always
届かない夢見て
dreaming of an unreachable dream.
騒ぐ頭の中を
Stirring up the noise inside her head,
掻き回して、
spinning it around,
掻き回して。
spinning it around.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
Sighing "No problem,"
言葉は失われた？
have her words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しに終われば、
If it ends in searching for mistakes,
また、回るの！
it rolls again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私々は今日も転がります。」と、
"I will roll again today," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl, the girl,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
playing with the meaning of her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「まだですよ、」// "Not yet,"
"Not yet,"
「まだまだ先は見えないので。」
"the future is still far from sight."
「息を止めるの、今。」
"So I'm holding my breath, just now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The wreckage of the rolling girl,
届かない、向こうの色
beyond the colors she can't reach.
重なる声と声を
Those overlapping voices in the air,
混ぜあわせて、
she mixes them all around,
混ぜあわせて。
mixes them all around.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
Sighing "No problem,"
言葉は失われた。
the words vanished.
今！
Now!
あ！
Ah!
いやぁ！
Yay!
チャオ、エブリワン！
Ciao, everyone!
チャオ、チャッティーニ！
Ciao, chattini!
はーい！ホロライブEnglish・Justiceのラオラ・パンテーラだよ！
Hi! It's me, Raora Panthera from Hololive English - Justice!
ラオー！猫が…
Rawr! The cat is...
…大きなステージに！
...on the big stage!
うわぁ、これ見て！おぉ！
Oh my god, look at this! Oh!
ここは何の場所？何でここにいるの？
What is this place? Why are we here?
それに…
And also...
…今日は何の日？何の日だっけ？もしかして…
...what day is it? What day is it? Is it...
…もしかして、私の誕生日？！
...is it my birthday?!
いぇーい！
Yay!
この特別な日に来てくれて、みんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you everyone for being here on this special day!
みんなに会えてすごく嬉しい！チャオチャオチャオチャオチャオ！
I'm so happy to see everyone! Ciao ciao ciao ciao ciao!
みんなハロー！誕生日のことなんだけど…
Hi everyone! And talking about my birthday...
…今日の特別なハッシュタグがあるんだ！
...I have a special hashtag for today,
それは、#Raorabday2026！
which is #Raorabday2026!
うぉー！だからみんな、もしスクリーンショットをシェアしたり…
Woo! So everyone make sure, if you want to share some screenshots...
…SNSにコメントを投稿したいときは、
...and you want to share some comments on social media,
ぜひこのハッシュタグを使ってね！本当にありがとう！
make sure to use this hashtag! Thank you so much!
あ、でもまずは、このステージを見てみよう！
But maybe now we should take a look at... this stage!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
すごく…すごく大きいよね？なんだかちょっと…
It's so... it's so big, isn't it? It's a little bit like...
本当に夢の中みたい。夢の中にいるみたい。
It looks really dreamy, like we are in a dream.
もしかして私、寝てる？寝てるのかな。おぉ！
Maybe I'm sleeping? Maybe I'm sleeping. Whoa!
わぁ！シュルレアリスムみたいな感じだね。
Whoa! It's like surrealism, kind of thing.
ここ、本当にどこなんだろう？私は…おっ、おぉ！
What is this place? What am I... whoa!
おぉ！えっ？えぇ？！
Whoa! Huh? Huh?!
私の…私のアイドル衣装？何で？えっ？
My... my idol outfit? What? Huh?
何で今アイドル衣装を着てるの？もしかしてこれって…
Why my idol outfit now? Maybe that means...
…もっと歌えってことかな？
...I should sing more?
それなら、歌っちゃおう！だから、私の歌を聴いてね！
Well, might as well! So please, listen to my songs!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes and make sure of it
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see
私ここでまた見ることできるの？
the future I lost from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を
No matter how many times I have to tear through
何度も裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
the overflowing shadows of anxiety, I'll walk through this world
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ
Time ticks away endlessly, announcing a new beginning now
変わらない思いをのせ
Carrying our unchanging feelings
閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if we come to a halt on a difficult road...
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれる
...the sky always waits for us with its beautiful blue
だから怖くない
So I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
I won't falter, no matter what happens anymore
振り返れば仲間がいて
When I look back, my friends are there
気がつけば優しく包まれてた
And before I knew it, I was gently enveloped by them
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything was distorted...
唯一信じれるここが救いだった
...this place, the only thing I could believe in, was my salvation
喜びも悲しみもわけあえば強まる想い
Sharing both joy and sadness only strengthens our feelings
この声が届くのなら
If this voice can reach you
きっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
I'm sure we can make a miracle happen
交わした約束
The promise we made...
忘れないよ
...I won't forget.
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to confirm it.
押し寄せた闇
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness
振り払って進むよ
and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is,
越えてみせるからきっと
I'll definitely overcome it.
明日信じて
Believe in tomorrow...
祈って
...and pray.
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in a broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように
...was drawn to you,
辿り着いた
and I've finally arrived.
目覚めた心は
The awakened heart
走り出した
starts running
未来を描くため
to draw the future.
難しく道で立ち止まっても
Even if we stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれる
the sky is always a beautiful blue and waiting for us.
だから怖くない
That's why I'm not afraid,
もう何があっても挫けない
no matter what happens, I won't give up anymore.
ずっと
Always...
明日待って
...waiting for tomorrow.
Yay! Woo!
Oh, hug! Hug!
Happy birthday!
Thank you, Kronii! Thank you!
I'm so excited for you! It's your first 3D birthday live!
It is! And look at us with our other outfit!
I know, we are so gorgeous.
So cool! I'm so cool!
You are.
I am so cool.
And, you know, because you're so cool, I want to give you...
...a beautiful color that I think would suit you.
Me? / Yes.
Which color? Pink? Is it going to be pink?
Um, it's... If you look at your eyes, your beautiful yellow eyes...
...they have curiosity and playfulness.
And I think it suits you.
And so I would like to give this color, this beautiful color around us.
Which color?
Are you colorblind?
You don't have to bully me on my birthday! You're supposed to be nice to me!
I am! I said your beautiful yellow eyes...
...it's beautiful, it's like golden!
Why use my birthday to give me a gift, and you come here, you sing and dance with me...
...and then you just start bullying me?
You know what? Get out of here!
I complimented you! I complimented you!
Golden! Golden eyes! Isn't that beautiful?
So it's kind of like yellow, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, what does it mean? Why, why did you give this color to me?
Like, I just said: curiosity and playfulness.
Were you not listening to me? You don't care about me.
My bad, you talk too much.
I'm sorry!
I want... my throat!
Sorry, I have a...
I think you should keep up your dream.
I have a question. / Okay, I have an answer.
Oh, yes.
Like, I was expecting blue coming from you.
Why yellow?
Why are you making me laugh?
Is it because of the yellow?
It's... it's your... it's just, everything is so...
You're obsessed with my eyes.
Your eyes are so beautiful.
Were you expecting blue? Because I thought you were like... sad, and...
Well, you don't have a blue color scheme in your...
Oh, yeah. But, you're blue!
Yeah, but it's because...
I know! I give you blue.
Oh, thank you!
Yeah. What does that mean?
Loneliness, sadness, fear, maybe?
Oh... oh. That's... why would you give that to me?
Because... I thought you liked me.
I like you! What?
You... you invited me all the way here, and you gave me this beautiful color, and you give me blue?
But because you're so pretty! Like blue.
I'm so... yeah. And you're so pretty!
Oh, stop!
You stop.
No, you stop.
No, stop!
You know what? We can maybe blend blue and pink together to get...
Purple.
Never mind.
What does purple mean?
What does purple mean? I don't know, we'll find out!
Oh. Whoa, purp... you just spoiled it!
We will find out, I guess! I don't know.
There's... to be continued, everyone.
To be continued, everyone! So keep watching our... my... my... not "our". That's not your birthday, it's my birthday!
It is... it is your birthday.
It is my birthday! So, we're gonna keep watching, everyone! We're gonna... I'm gonna keep singing and dancing for you, okay?
Whoa, whoa! And be sure to use her hashtag, okay?
Yes!
Hell yeah!
Raora Bday 2026!
Yeah! Hell yeah!
Ciao ciao!
Also, thank you Kronii for coming.
Oh, yeah, you're welcome.
I forgot to thank you.
Oh, yeah, thank you for having me.
Thank you for singing and dancing with me, it was so fun!
Yay!
Okay, keep up the good work!
Keep... keep the good work!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Ciao ciao!
左手に隠した願いは願いのままで
Wishes hidden in my left hand remain as they are,
覚めない幻見てた
having dreamed an endless dream.
右手には空の記憶
In my right hand, a hollow memory.
誰も知らない世界の果て
At the edge of a world unknown to anyone,
やまない雨にうたれていた
I was pelted by the ceaseless rain.
守りたいものを守れる強さ
The strength to protect what I want to protect,
それを信じられなくなる弱さ
the weakness that stops me from believing in it...
すべてを受け入れて 未来を探す
Accepting everything, I search for the future.
Brave shine 手を伸ばせばまだ
Brave shine, if I reach out my hand,
Stay the night 傷だらけの夜
Stay the night, there's still a scarred night.
You save my life かざした刃の先に想いを重ねた
You save my life, overlapping feelings at the tip of the raised blade.
祈りは時を越えて
Our prayers transcend time.
Your brave shine
光る事忘れた 青い星が残していく
Forgot how to shine, the blue star leaves behind...
消えない影見てた
watching the unerasable shadow.
すれ違う赤の軌道
A passing red trajectory.
何も知らない子供のまま
Like a child who knows nothing,
明けない夜を彷徨ってた
wandering through the endless night.
失くせないものを失くした弱さ
The weakness of losing what can't be lost,
何も信じられなくなる脆さ
the fragility of losing faith in everything...
立てなくなっても 運命は進む
Even if I can no longer stand, fate moves forward...
...運命は進む...
...fate moves forward...
Break down
崩れ落ちてゆく星座が
The crumbling constellations
傷つけ合う夜
Nights where we hurt each other
You're breaking dawn
交わした言葉の中に
In the exchanged words
一人を支えた
Supporting one another
確かな夢を
Accompanied by a certain dream
添えて
Keeping it close...
守りたいものを守れるのなら
If I can protect what I want to protect
全てを受け入れて 明日を探す
Accepting everything, I'll search for tomorrow
夜明けを灯す
Lighting up the dawn
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
If I reach out my hand, there's still
Stay the night
傷だらけの夜
A night full of scars
You save my life
重ねた涙の果てに
Finding light at the end
光を見つけた
Of our layered tears
祈りは時を越えて
Prayers transcend time
My brave shine
Woo! Happy Birthday, Raora!
おめでとう！誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy Birthday!
Shall we introduce ourselves?
Of course, please do!
Great. 自己紹介お願いします、先輩。
Great. Please introduce yourself, Senpai.
Introduction, okay? Please!
こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の、えっと...
Kon-yappi! Hololive 4th Generation's... um...
オールド先輩の常闇トワ様でーす！
...'old' senpai, Tokoyami Towa-sama!
オールド先輩！イェーイ！常闇先輩！
Old senpai! Yay! Towa-senpai!
オールド先輩か... Oh, really?
An 'old' senpai, huh? Oh, really?
ちょっと待って、Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-senpai!
Wait a minute, Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-senpai!
What?! Okay fine, hello!
えー、みなさん、オールド先輩、森カリオペでーす！
Uh, hello everyone! 'Old' senpai, Mori Calliope here!
From Hololive English -Myth-. What's up, fellow pink? Fellow pink!
Yeah! Pink is powerful!
Towa-sama, you're also pink! We're kind of...
Of course! Different shades of pink, right? Yeah, colors are so important in this life, so...
...we must say that this is the pink team, right? Yeah, pink team.
Pink-purple team, yeah. Pink-purple team, お願いいたします！
Pink-purple team, yeah. Pink-purple team, here we go!
Nice! Wonderful!
But you know, the lighting actually when we were singing the song that we just sang a moment ago was blue!
Yeah, it was blue! So pretty, right? Look at that!
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents? どんな感情？Blue.
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents? What kind of emotion? Blue.
ブルー。ブルーは結構、寂しいとか...
Blue. Blue is kind of like loneliness...
...そういう悲しいみたいなイメージはあるけど、でも綺麗なイメージもあるよ。
...it has that sad image, but it also has a beautiful image too.
Yeah, also beautiful. Sad, lonely, also beautiful.
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? 怖さ (kowasa). A little scary, right?
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? Fear. A little scary, right?
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? 感情がめっちゃ美しいと思う。
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? I think emotions are really beautiful.
So, positive, negative, either way I think colors are really beautiful.
I agree with you! And you know, even if sometimes we have fear and we're scared of doing something, maybe...
...maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know...
怖くても、頑張らないといけないね。
Even if we're scared, we have to do our best, right?
例えば、singing on stage together...
For example, singing on stage together...
...speaking Japanese! It's so scary! You just gotta try your best, throw your fears away. 怖くないよ！
...speaking Japanese! It's so scary! You just gotta try your best, throw your fears away. It's not scary!
How do you overcome? It's so scary! We just sang Brave Shine!
Brave Shine! We just sang!
Such a good song! It's very fitting. Right! Yeah, fight your fears! 怖くないね。
Such a good song! It's very fitting. Right! Yeah, fight your fears! It's not scary.
勇気持って (yuuki motte). Courage. And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Have courage. Courage. And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Yeah! But fears are also part of our lives, right? Like, maybe if we're not... if we don't feel the fear...
...then, how can we overcome? Like, how can we do... how to say... how can we do...
I don't know that word... like...
How can we challenge our past selves? How can we challenge ourselves and do...
...our best every single day, right?
怖くなかったら、まあ、チャレンジじゃないよね。
If it wasn't scary, well, it wouldn't be a challenge, would it?
怖かったらもっと強くなれると思う。You can become stronger if it's scary.
If it's scary, I think you can become even stronger. You can become stronger if it's scary.
かっこいい！ねえ、おぉー！
So cool! Wow!
なにか意味深？
Is there a deep meaning?
Deep meaning! That's cool.
かっこいいね！
That's so cool!
Cute and cool, Raora!
Raora can do it!
You are cool.
Everyone, everyone here is cool. / みんなクール！
Everyone, everyone here is cool. / Everyone's cool!
Pink is very cool.
Pink's a cool color, okay? Hey.
Well, happy birthday to you.
Thank you so much, Mori!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！ Happy birthday!
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
Thank you guys! Thank you for singing Brave Shine with me.
It's a very meaningful song, and...
I really appreciate to have my dai-senpais with me! Thank you so much!
Yeah, of course! Old senpai, old senpai is here with you.
Well, myself and Towa got to get out of here, but Raora, you keep on keeping on, okay?
Okay, I'll do my best then!
Yeah, and we'll see you guys later, okay?
See you guys later!
Bye everybody! Bye-bye!
白い世界の中では
In a white-colored world
時間は止まってゆくような気がした
it seemed as if time had stopped
いつも見せないような
An expression you don't usually show,
表情が その距離が少しだけ愛しかった
and that distance was just a little endearing
巻き戻せないと
Realizing it can't be rewound,
はしゃいでいるその横顔
I look at your side profile in high spirits
抱えていた悩みも
Even the worries I held...
ちっぽけだ
...seem so small
君に染まる視界が
My field of vision dyed by you,
かじかんでく両手が
and my freezing hands...
心から願うよ 終わらせたくなどはないんだと
...pray from my heart, wishing this would never end
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
Your figure is always in my memories
夢のまま 覚めないまま
Like a dream, without waking up,
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I can't forget that smile
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult
くだらない事ばっか
Full of meaningless things,
それでも楽しかった
yet it was fun nonetheless
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
It'd be nice if this moment could go on forever
なんてさ僕に はにかんでみせるの
You shyly said to me,
泣きそうな声で
with a tearful voice
新しい世界では
In this new world,
きっと心から笑えているかな
I wonder if you're laughing from your heart
謝りたいな
I want to apologize,
見せる顔なんてないよ
but I can't even show my face to you
僕は君の思う未来のどこにもいないようだ
It seems I'm nowhere in the future you envision
逃げ出したくないよ
I don't want to run away,
あの日に戻りたくなるよ
yet I want to go back to that day
振り向いてばかりの人生ならば 諦めよう
If life is only about looking back, let's give up
いたいけな祈りも
Even this innocent prayer,
確かめたい気持ちも
and these feelings I want to confirm...
今なら言えるだろうか
...can I say them now?
終わらせたくはないんだと知る
I know that I don't want it to end
何度も言うよ 景色は儚げに
I'll say it again and again, the scenery is ephemeral
足元はおぼつかない
My footsteps are unsteady,
気付けば走り出していたんだ
before I knew it, I was running
何度も言うよ
I'll say it again and again,
会いたい言葉など 見つかるわけでもない
though I can't find words like 'I want to meet you'
それでもただ信じてみたいから
Still, I just want to try and believe
思い出の中君の姿
Your figure in my memories
夢のまま 覚めないまま
Like a dream, without waking up,
変わらないな
remains unchanged
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
Your figure is always in my memories
夢のまま 覚めないまま
Like a dream, without waking up,
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I can't forget that smile
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult
くだらない事ばっか それでも楽しかった
Full of meaningless things, yet it was fun nonetheless
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
It'd be nice if this moment could go on forever
ずっと今がこのまんま続いたらいいな
I wish this moment could last forever.
今度は私からハッピーを届けてみせるの
This time, I will deliver happiness to you.
約束しよう
Let's make a promise.
約束をしよう
The Everlasting Guilty Crown
世界は終わりを告げようとしてる
The world is about to meet its end.
誰にももう止められはしない
No one can stop it anymore.
――始まる
...It begins.
崩壊の交響曲が鳴り響いて
As the symphony of collapse echoes,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
the falling rain sounds like tears.
教えて
Tell me...
支配し支配され人々は
ruling and being ruled, will people
いつかその心に憎しみを
keep harboring hatred in their hearts...
そして愛することを思い出せず 争うの？
...and fight on, unable to remember how to love?
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
生命ある全ての者よ
All living things...
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
the truth lies within your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when crossing stormy seas,
決して臆することのない強さを
it will give you the strength
くれるから
to never shrink in fear.
けれども進むほど風は強く
But the further you go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope will eventually fade.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Clashing over the light, shouting "give it to me,"
果てに人は殺し合う
in the end, people kill one another.
涙などとうに枯れて
Their tears have long run dry.
気付いて
Realize this...
その目は互いを認めるため
those eyes are meant to recognize each other,
その声は想いを伝えるため
those voices are meant to convey feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
and those hands are meant to connect with loved ones.
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
All the stray souls of this world...
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
hope lies within your heart.
燃え盛る焔の中でも
Even in the midst of a blazing fire,
決して傷つくことのない強さを
it will give you the strength
くれるから
to never be hurt.
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was the thing you tried to protect with those hands...
愛する者だったのだろうか
...truly someone you loved?
紅く染まったその手を眺めて
Staring at those hands stained in red,
やっと自らがしてきた愚かさを
you finally realize the foolishness of your actions...
過ちと認めるその罪を
...and acknowledge your mistakes and sins...
とめどなくあふれるその涙を知る
...as you learn of tears overflowing endlessly.
…者よ
...beings
真実は あなたの胸の中にある
The truth is in your heart.
嵐の海は静まった
The stormy sea has calmed down.
失ったものは数えきれなくとも
Even if the things lost are countless...
この歌が聴こえてる
Can you hear this song?
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
All helpless people in the world,
希望は あなたの胸の中にある
Hope is in your heart.
悲しみの夜を超える時
When crossing the night of sorrow,
必ずあなたは生きていく
you will surely go on living...
強さを持てるから
with the strength to survive.
やった！できた！
We did it! We did it!
Fluffy tail! Fluffy tail!
お互いのしっぽを見せ合おう！
Let's show off our tails!
おお、揺れてる！
Whoa, sway, sway!
どっちの方が長いの？ / 私の方が長いよ！
Which one is longer? / Mine is longer!
ハッピーバースデー、ラオーラ！
Happy birthday, Raora! Happy birthday!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being here!
彼女を見て！彼女を見て！
Look at her! Look at her!
自己紹介しなきゃ！
You should introduce yourself!
あ、こんにちは！あなたは誰？この不思議な生き物は誰？
Oh, hi! Who are you? Who is this mysterious creature?
耳は何個あるの？
How many ears do you have?
私は不思議な生き物… / 1、2、3、4…
I'm a mysterious creature... / One, two, three, four...
4、5、6、7… / 4つだよ！6つ、7つの耳？
Four, five, six, seven... / It's four! Six, seven ears?
自己紹介してよ！
Who are you? Introduce yourself!
ハロー、チャットのみんな、こんにちは！私はジェリク。4つの耳を持つ狐で、ここにいる本日の主役の自称親友です！
Hello, hi chat! Hi. I'm Geriku, and I am a four-eared fox and self-proclaimed best friend of the birthday girl over here!
私のこと大好きなんだよね？ / 大好きだよ！
She loves me very much, doesn't she? / I love her very much!
来てくれて本当にありがとう！ / 呼んでくれてありがとう！一緒に踊れて嬉しかったよ。
Yeah, thank you so much for being here! / Thank you for having me! It was so nice to dance with you.
今日はあなたにたくさんのパッションを届けに来たんだ… / パッション…
I have come here today to bring you a lot of passion... / Passion...
…それと、あなたが毎日美しいアートを描く時に解き放つべき、強い決意をね！
...and determination that you need to unleash when you do your beautiful art every single day!
これからはもっと情熱的になるよ！
I will be very passionate from now on!
今すぐ解き放ってほしいの！もう待てない、ずっと踊ってたんだから！手を貸して、手を貸して！
I need you to unleash it now! I can't wait any longer, I've been dancing this whole time! Give me your hand, give me your hand!
解き放って！悪魔を呼び覚ますんだ！
Unleash it! Unleash the demon!
みんなごめんね、もう行かなきゃ。見てくれてありがとう！
Sorry guys, I have to go now. Thank you so much for watching!
いや、まだだよ！私の人生を続けるんだ！ / みんな本当にありがとう！バイバイ！
No, not yet! You will continue my life! / Thank you so much everyone! I'm going to leave you.
行かせないよ！置いてかないで！ / 置いていくよ！…次の曲のダンスは知ってる？
No, she won't! Don't leave me! / I'm going to leave you! ...Do you know the dances for the next song?
すごく楽しいから、あなたも… / 私も？参加してほしいの？
It's going to be very fun. You should... / I... You want me to join?
そうそう！いや、今すぐライブをやらなきゃ。本番だよ！ / 今すぐ生でやらなきゃいけないの？！
Yeah, yeah! No, no, you have to do the live now. It's live! / I have to do it live now?!
準備はいい？よし、いつでもいけるよ。やろう！ / イエス！うわぁ！
Ready? All right, I'm ready. Let's do it! / Yes! Whoa!
よし！決意を解き放つんだ！そうだ、そうだ、踊れ、踊れ、踊れ！
Yes! Unleash the determination! Yes, yes, yes, dance, dance, dance, dance!
そして今度は、バースデーガールの番だよ！ / うわぁ、ちょっと待って！
And now, birthday girl time! / Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
わぁ！ヘイヘイヘイ！
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey!
見ちゃった！見ちゃったよ！ / 見、見ちゃダメだよ！見えた？
I saw that! I saw that! / You can... you can't see that! Did you see that?
私は見ちゃったよ。 / 見てないよ！ステージからやるべきだよ。
Because I saw it. / No, you didn't see it! You should do it from the stage.
まあ、一緒にお風呂（温泉）に入ったんだから、全部見ただろ。これ以上見なくていいよ！
Well, we've been to onsen together, you... you saw everything. You don't have to see anything else!
なんて乱暴なの！でもいいよ、素晴らしい！決意が現れてる、パッションが…
Oh god, you're so violent! That's good, that's good! The determination is coming out, the passion is...
…パッションがここに！あぁ、情熱！ / 全てのパッション！情熱的になるよ！
...the passion is here! Oh, the passion! / All the passion! I'll be passionate!
その調子でお願い。テンションMAXだからさ。リラックスして。無理だよ。
The passion, please. I'm hype max, please. Relax. I can't do that.
おいで、おいで、おばあちゃん。こっち来て。 / あぁ、いいよ。おしゃべりしたいんだね。絶対おしゃべりしたいんだ。
Oh, come here, come here, grandma. Come here. / Ah, this is okay. She wants to talk. She definitely wants to talk.
私がおしゃべりしたいの？何について話したい？
I want to talk? What do you want to talk about?
あなたが話したがってるって言ったの。 / 話したいよ。 / 私をおばあちゃんって呼んだね。よくもそんなことを！
I said, you want to talk. / I want to talk. / You called me grandma. How freaking dare you?
よくも言ったな！ちょっと、私のこと「自称」って呼んだでしょ…
How freaking dare you! Hey, you called me self-proclaimed...
この動き、全部私がやったんだからね。クレイジーなダンスを全部。そうそうそう。
All these moves, I pulled out, you know. All the crazy dances. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
本当に大変なダンスだったよね？すっごく難しかった。
Right, that was such a tough dance, wasn't it? Oh, it was so hard.
彼女が誕生日祝いでディナーをごちそうしてくれるんだって！ / そう、私の誕生日！
She's going to treat me for dinner to celebrate her birthday! / Yeah, it's my birthday!
そうそうそう。あなたが…あなたがディナーをごちそうしてくれるべきだよ。 / 何を買ってくれるの？何を用意してくれる？
Yes, yes, yes. You should... you should treat me for dinner. / What are you going to get for me? What are you going to get for me?
実は… / 何をくれるのかな？楽しみだな。
Actually... / What are you going to get for me? Good points here.
No, no, no.
Oh yeah, because you guys know...
No, we have to close the camera... no, that's fine.
I'm so...
You're so what? You said...
I'm so not done!
I'm going to give you...
...ten dollars!
Absolutely not!
Yeah! Thank you, Rico!
That hasn't happened yet!
No! Thank you!
Thank you, thank you!
It's over!
You know my data for the pay, okay?
Hey, come back!
I don't want to send you money anymore.
Ah yeah, you got it.
You owe me forty pounds already, mate.
It's friend taxes, okay?
She is so in debt with me.
And she takes... this is really bad of her.
It's my birthday, I decide what I want.
And I decide everything.
If I want ten dollars, you're gonna give me ten dollars.
What should I do?
What should I do? The drama...
Chatty, please tell her!
Tell her to give me ten dollars!
Chat, I can't. You look so determined.
You really want this money.
Fine...
Here it is. Just buy yourself some chocolate, okay?
One more, one more.
I'm so done. Live on stream...
Oh my god, it's over.
Oh, the mortgage, oh, the car, oh, the insurance...
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay, don't talk about negative things now.
Cuz today, it's my birthday, we gotta celebrate!
Did you bring cake for us?
Ah...
Yes.
Where is it?
Actually, the cake?
I'm waiting!
Ah, wait, I can tell now.
Cake, cake, cake, cake, cake...
No, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Cake!
Wait, wait, no, no, that's my tail!
Hey, hey, I grabbed your tail.
Come here!
Come here! No, no!
It's kind of easy to do, it's very long.
Listen, listen, listen, you need to walk...
...you need to run way faster if you want me...
No, no, no, no! Oh, you know what then? I'll grab yours.
No! No! Come!
I got it, I got it, I got it. I'm taking a bite.
Manager! Oh, manager's zone.
What is manager going to do now?
And she's not going to be happy with it.
You know what? I'm going to go and talk to your manager by myself.
No, you cannot talk to my manager! I talk to my manager!
I'm so done. I'm done.
No, you're not. Actually, we're done.
But that was still a great workout. We really did...
...deserve cake after all.
Ah, we deserve cake after all, isn't it? What's your favorite flavor?
My favorite flavor is...
...Rico-tail!
Okay, we have to go now. We have to go.
There's more to come. There's so much more.
She has so many surprises for you. Yippee!
You are the surprise.
Am I? No, am I? No.
But I have more surprises. She does, she does, she does.
So thank you so much, Rico!
Happy birthday, Raora! Rico!
Yippee! Thank you for having me!
Pink creature! Pink creature!
Ooh, great creature. Oh, yes.
Yes, actually, talking about colors, you should put some colors on.
Well, I bought some new glasses today, nice and red, you should see them.
I'll show you them sometime soon.
Yippee! Next song! Next song!
More songs! More songs to come!
Happy birthday! Yeah, thank you, Rico!
Hi Chatty-ni!
Okay, then, ta-ta!
Bye-bye! Bye!
Bye!
言って。
Say it.
あのね、
Hey,
私実は気気付いてるの
I've actually noticed it.
ほら、君がいったこと
Look, that thing you said.
あまり
I couldn't really...
考えたいと思えなくて
...think about it too much,
忘れてたんだけど
and I had forgotten it, but...
盲目的に盲動的に妄想的に生きて
I lived blindly, recklessly, delusionally.
衝動的な焦燥的な
Living keeping that impulsive, impatient,
消極的なままじゃ駄目だったんだ
passive state was no good.
きっと人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
I'm sure that before the final day of my life I'll think...
全部 全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
...of how regrettable it is that I couldn't say everything, everything.
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないこと
Ahh, someday on the last day of my life, that you're not here...
もっと もっと もっと もっと もっと
...more, more, more, more, more...
ちゃんと言って
...tell me properly.
あのね
Hey, you know...
空が青いのってどうやって
...how do I convey that the sky is blue?
伝えればいいんだろうね
How should I say it?
夜の
The night...
雲が高いのってどうすれば
...how do I make you understand how high the clouds are?
君もわかるんだろう
I wonder if you can understand too.
言って
Say it.
あのね
Hey, you know...
私 実はわかってるの
...honestly, I already know...
もう君が逝ったこと
...that you're already gone.
あのね
Hey, you know...
わからずやって言うんだろうね
You'll probably call me stubborn...
忘れたいんだけど
...though I want to forget.
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
Tell me more properly.
忘れないようメモにしてよ
Write a memo so I won't forget.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet up at the train platform tomorrow at ten.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Even when the peony scatters, it's still a flower.
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even when summer passes, the yearning is deep.
口に出して
Put it into words.
声に出して
Say it out loud.
君が言って
You say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And if I can see you on the last day of my life...
きっと 人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
...surely I'll sing of love on the last day of my life, too.
全部 全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
Because I'll say that none of it, none of it was in vain.
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことが
Ahh, someday on the last day of my life, that you're not here...
まだ信じられないけど
...is still hard for me to believe, but...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
...more, more, more, more...
もっと もっと もっと 君が
...more, more, more, you...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
...more, more, more, more...
もっと
...more...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
...more, more, more, more...
もっと
...more...
ちゃんと言って
...properly, say it to me.
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
Ah, thank you so much for being here, Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
I can't believe we sang together!
So fun!
いやいや、こちらこそありがとう！
No, no, thank you!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
次のゲストは、みお先輩とおかゆ先輩です！
The next guests are Mio-senpai and Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！ラオラ！
Yay! Raora!
Happy birthday!
Thank you!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Thank you! 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！
Our pleasure!
Why don't you introduce yourselves one more time?
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
オッケー！
Okay!
うち、うち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
Uchi, uchi, it's uchi! I'm Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
かわいい！そして...
So cute! And...
はーい！
Okay!
もぐもぐ、おかゆ！
Mogu mogu, Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
もぐもぐ、おかゆ！もぐもぐ、おかゆ！
Mogu mogu, Okayu! Mogu mogu, Okayu!
もぐもぐ、もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu
Yummy yummy! Yummy yummy!
Thank you so much! ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you very much!
よし、行くぞ！
Alright, let's go!
えーっと、Mio's English Challenge!
Um, Mio's English Challenge!
The glow writing in the concert was beautiful, wasn't it?
おかゆず、イングリッシュ・チャレンジ！
Okayu's English Challenge!
おー！
Oh!
"Self-symbolize, sincerity, and self-acceptance."
"Hey, you don't have to try to be strong or try to be perfect."
おおー！
Wow!
"That's right!"
"Just accept yourself as you are, and go with the flow, and you'll be fine."
わぁー！
Wow!
Can I be strong? Strong, strong!
I want to be a strong big cat!
Big cat!
Yes!
Raora, strong cat!
Thank you, Senpais, for your nice words!
Thank you! Thank you!
心に響きました。
It touched my heart.
よかった、よかった。
I'm glad, I'm glad.
From here, I've got some exciting news for you guys!
It's about the Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
イェーイ！
Yay!
So, please, Senpais, help me out, okay?
記念グッズ紹介、お手伝いします！任せて！
We'll help you introduce the commemorative merchandise! Leave it to us!
Okay, so... Raora Panthera 誕生日記念 2026...
Okay, so... Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026...
グッズの、 26!
merchandise's... 26!
グッズ情報！
Merchandise details!
Okay, okay! Let's go, let's go! Let's go!
Take a look here! こちらどうぞ！
Take a look here! Here you go!
おおー！すごいね！
Wow! Amazing!
So good! Look at this illustration! Do you like it?
好き！すごい可愛い！
I love it! It's so cute!
The illustration was drawn by Komiya-sensei! Thank you so much for making this beautiful art! I'm so happy!
胡宮先生に描いてもらったみたいです！
It looks like Komiya-sensei drew this for you!
ライブのRaoraをテーマに描いてもらったみたいですね。
It seems it was drawn with the theme of Raora's live concert!
Okay, so let's take a closer look at the details! First up, this one!
おおー！
Wow!
Long Sleeve T-shirt!
ロンTシャツ！
A long-sleeve T-shirt!
It features my live logo on the back, and there's also design on the sleeves, so it's really, really cool for everyday life!
So, please check it out! 可愛い！
So, please check it out! Cute!
ね、なんかロゴとかも付いててね、いっぱいデザインが凝ってて可愛いね。
Right, it has a logo and stuff, and the design has a lot of detail, so it's cute.
すごい、すごい！
Amazing, amazing!
And next, we have... ta-da!
Crossbody Bag!
ボディバッグ！ボディバッグ！
Oh, a crossbody bag!
Body bag, I like it.
And it's a bag designed for everyday use that lets you show off your love for... me!
Raora推しをアピールできる普段使いできるバッグになっております。
It's a bag for everyday use that lets you show off your support for Raora.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
Thank you! Next up is... ta-da!
Punished Chattini! 可愛い！
Punished Chattini! Cute!
Punished Chattini, that's what you deserve! That's what you get!
まあ、まあ、まあ。
Now, now, now.
Punished Chattini that comes with an amazing pouch! Next, please!
Next, please!
おおー！
Wow!
Perfect! You can combine them together!
チャッティーニが洗濯機の中に閉じ込められちゃったみたいです。
It looks like Chattini got locked inside the washing machine.
ぐるぐるぐる。
Round and round.
はい、こちらね、チャッティーニが閉じ込められてるのは、ぬいぐるみ用のマルチポーチですね。
Yes, this item holding Chattini is a multi-pouch for plushies.
すごい可愛い！可愛い！
So cute! Cute!
And next up is... ta-da! Voice Pack!
Yes, it's gonna be fun to listen to it, so please check it out!
はい、Raoraがね、あの収録、頑張って収録したボイス。
Yes, the voice track that Raora worked hard to record.
聴いてみてくださいね、皆さんね。お願いします！
Please listen to it, everyone. Thank you!
And, there's also a bonus for purchasing the full set. And here it is!
おおー！
Wow!
The limited-quantity items are... Check out style photo with...
...とメッセージ、サイン
...with a message and a signature.
サイン！サイン、サイン！
A signature! A signature, signature!
こちらは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがフルセットに付いてきます！
This full set comes with a handwritten signed Instax-style photo card!
おおー！すごい！
Oh, awesome!
And... Instax-style bro... bromide...
英語難しい！
English is so hard!
英語難しかった！
English was hard!
難しい。
It's hard.
Difficult English!
With foil-stamped repro... reproduction... repro... repro...
I can't... I can't talk anymore! Signature, woo!
わぁー！
Yay!
ちなみにサインは数量限定となっております！
By the way, the signed ones are limited in quantity!
はい！お願いします。
Yes! Please check it out.
お願いします。
Please check it out.
Here is the full set again, so please go check it out, everyone! Thank you, thank you!
And that was the merch lineup for Raora Panthera's Birthday Celebration 2026!
Thank you so much, Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai! Thank you so much for your support!
Thank you so much!
こちらこそ！上手にフォローできたかな？
Likewise! Did we support you well?
どうかな？できたかな？
I wonder? Did we?
Thank you!
でも、すっごく楽しかったです！
But it was so much fun!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
楽しかった！ありがとう、嬉しい。
It was fun! Thank you, I'm so happy.
Alright, now that the merch announcement is done...
the next song will be the last one, 最後。
...the next song will be the last one. The last one.
最後？
The last one?
Last song!
楽しみ！
Can't wait!
I'm kind of nervous...
Please cheer for me, okay, senpais?
おーけー、おーけー！
Okay, okay!
がんばれがんばれ、らおらー！ファイト、ファイト！
Do your best, Raora! Fight, fight!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあ、バイバイ、Let's say goodbye!
Well then, bye-bye. Let's say goodbye!
オッケー、オッケー！
Okay, okay!
バイバ〜イ！
Bye-bye!
Draw.
夢のぬくもりと
The warmth of a dream, and...
指先に絵の具の匂い
...the scent of paint on my fingertips.
湿ったキャンバスの上には
On the damp canvas...
まだ知らない色が息をする
...a color I don't know yet breathes.
All the pieces I picked up
Unravel in my own chest
"It's okay," I whisper softly
Saving it back to myself
迷いも震えも
Neither my hesitation nor my trembling...
隠さなくていいから
...do I need to hide anymore.
この線の全部が
Every single one of these lines...
私へ続く
...leads to who I am.
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outlines...
淡く、脆く、煌めいて形になってゆくの
...faintly, fragilely, glitter and take shape.
夜明けの面影に
In the vestiges of dawn...
集めた色を重ね
...I layer the colors I've gathered.
Draw it slow, draw it true
夜明けの夢現
The dreamlike state at dawn...
微睡に余白の答え
...and the answer in the margins of my slumber.
白いページに色が咲いていく
On the white page, colors begin to bloom...
息づいた景色を描き出す
...painting a scenery brought to life.
All the colors I held back
Start to gather in the hush
"It's all right," the first light tells me
Sending warmth into my heart
願いも希望も
Neither my wishes nor my hopes...
隠さなくていいんだよ
...do you need to hide anymore.
ほら、ありのままの
Look, just as you are...
私を描く
...I will draw myself.
At last, hold my true colors
ほどけた輪郭も
Even the unraveled outlines,
そっと、ずっと、重なって
are gently, forever overlapping,
私の形になる
becoming my shape.
静かな始まりに
In a quiet beginning,
目覚めた色を抱いて
embracing the awakened colors.
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outlines,
淡く、脆く、煌めいて
faintly, fragrantly shimmering,
形になってゆくの
taking shape.
夜明けの面影を
Gathering the traces of dawn,
集めた色で描く
I draw with the colors gathered.
draw it slow, draw it true
Ah...
La la la...
draw it slow, draw it true
夢のぬくもりと
Dream's warmth and
指先に絵の具の匂い
the scent of paint on my fingertips.
ありふれた朝の先には
Beyond the ordinary morning,
まだ知らない色が溢れてる
colors I don't know yet are overflowing.
Raoooo!
Ciao everyone! I'm still here.
I just wanted to say thank you so, so much...
...for watching my first ever 3D birthday live!
I had so much fun, and I hope you...
...I hope you had so much fun, too!
I worked really, really hard, and I'm so happy right now.
So thank you Chatini! Thank you everyone for watching!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching!
So, I have to go now. Bye-bye!
And remember, big cat means...
...big trouble!
Raoooo!
Ciao everyone! I have one last message for you all.
Be sure to check out the MV premiere right after this!
And also, my new original song will be releasing...
...on all streaming platforms on May 11th midnight...
...in your local timezone.
So don't miss it out, okay?
Also, go check out my merch!
Bye bye-bye!
Raoooo!
Bye-bye!